准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
章霸王
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村站
沉船镇  我来了
Jetsam City, here I come
这一定会是史上最棒周末
This is going to be the best weekend ever
章鱼哥
Squidward
海霸王
Bubble Bass
你该不会也要去沉船镇漫展吧
Don't tell me you're going to
the Jetsam City comic convention too
我怎么可能会浪费时间
Why would I waste my time
去逛什么白痴漫展
on an idiotic comic book convention?
我有着深深的文化造诣
I am a man of sophistication
要去竖笛大会
I'm going to the clarinet convention
拜托
Please
这才叫浪费时间呢
Talk about a waste of time
少不懂装懂了
Shows what you know
单是听个竖笛口水阀历史讲座
The lecture on the history of spit valves
都能值回票价了
is worth the price of admission alone
我之前说这才叫浪费时间
When I said talk about a waste of time
可不单单是说着玩的
I didn't mean literally
前往沉船镇的旅客请上车
All aboard for the train to Jetsam City
离我远一点
Just stay away from me
同上
Dit to the O
果不其然
Typical
我先
Dibs
继续走吧  小子
Keep walking, Bucko
真是的
Come on
你
You
你连占了两个座
You're taking up two seats
一边屁股一个座
One for each cheek
给我挪过去
Just move over
车上位置就剩这个了
It's the last seat on the train
好
Fine
别找我说话
And don't talk to me
早都吃完了
It's finished
那看来还要再来点吃的
Then it appears I need another snack
奶酪火锅车
The fondue cart
要奶酪火锅吗
Fondue, sir?
请给我来一大碗热到冒泡的吧
One bubbling bowl of melted cheese, please
你运气正好  先生
You're in luck, sir
我正好现做了热气腾腾的一大盘出来
I just made a fresh, piping hot batch
要多大的火锅呢
What size would you like?
我特地自带了个锅
I brought my own fondue pot
装满吧
Fill it to the rim
好的  先生
Yes, sir
小小小  小心点倒
Be-be-be careful with that
下一站  沉船镇
Next stop, Jetsam City
烫
Hot
你吃不吃呢
Are you going to eat that?
别碰我
Get off of me
艺术
别靠过来
Stay on your side
你们可真是一对好朋友啊
Well, aren't you two the best of friends
才不是
We are not
你想干嘛
Now, what do you want?
能不能帮忙照看我宝宝
Would you watch my baby
我得先去一趟卫生间
while I run to the restroom?
要方便很久才能出来
I have to powder my nose like a racehorse
谢了
Thanks
坐火车就是这个下场
This is what I get for traveling coach
奶酪火锅吃得我都流奶酪汗了
That fondue gave me the cheese sweats
爽啊
Refreshing
你都快害宝宝着凉了
You're making the baby cold
什么
What?
你上哪找来这么可爱的宝宝的
Where did you get such an adorable baby?
他肯定是要开窗
Who clearly wants the window open
宝宝要关窗
The baby wants it closed
宝宝要开窗
The baby wants it open
关窗
Closed
开窗
Open
关窗
Closed
开窗
Open
宝宝
The baby
我回来了
I'm back
宝宝呢
Where's my baby?
你真想知道吗
You really want to know?
希望她能找到宝宝
I hope she finds her baby
查票
Tickets
Tickets?
没票是吧
No tickets, huh?
我恨你
I loathe you
放心  宝贝
Don't you worry, baby
等妈妈找到那俩家伙
When Mommy finds those two
一定会禁足他们
she's gonna ground them
化他们为灰烬
Into dust
只能走过去了
I'm walking
不带点吃的吗
Without snacks?
我快饿坏了
I'm going to get hungry
你应该不会喜欢我饿肚子的样子
You won't like me when I'm hungry
我现在就不喜欢你
I don't like you now
我们就快死在这了
We're going to die out here
不至于
Maybe not
你看
Look
老头简金斯有块地
Old Man Jenkins has a farm
农场里有交通工具
And on that farm, he has a ride?
咿呀咿呀哟
E-I-E-I-O
这有拖拉机
With a tractor here
那有小马驹
And some horsies there
有条船
Here a boat
有自行车
There a bike
还有靴子能徒步
Everywhere are boots to hike
老头简金斯有飞机
Old Man Jenkins has a plane
咿呀咿呀
E-I-E-I-
啊对
Oh, yeah
别闹
Quit it
多谢你载我们一程
Thanks for the ride
也谢谢你送的鸡蛋沙拉三明治
And the egg salad sandwiches
你们运气正好
You folks are lucky
我正要去沉船镇
I was just heading into the city
领取新出的农夫年鉴呢
to pick up the new Farmer's Almanac
为了庆祝
To celebrate
那种三明治我得再吃一个
I think I will have another one of those sandwiches
你刚吃过了
You just ate
就快够到了
I can almost reach
别乱摇飞机
Stop shaking the plane
不然我马上迫降
or I'll pull this thing right over
谢谢
Thank you
好多了
Much better
现在该怎么办
Now what do we do?
可以把机尾当黄包车  我来坐你来拉
You could pull me using the plane tail as a rickshaw
我拉你
Me pull you?
全都要怪你
This is your fault
你才得拉我呢
You should pull me
翻硬币决定
We'll flip a coin
翻就翻
You're on
我够不到
I can't reach
你能捞出来吗
Could you fish it out?
算你赢
You win
欢迎光临
沉船镇
拖船大酒店
别把油漆刮花了
Don't scratch the paint
零钱不用找了
Keep the change
什么事
Yes?
章鱼哥预定的客房
Reservation for Squidward Tentacles
海霸王也预定了
And Bubble Bass
章鱼哥先生和海霸王先生
Mr. Tentacles and Mr. Bass
你们两个预定了我们最好的房间
You two have reserved our finest rooms
可以拿钥匙了吗
Can we just get our keys?
不行
No
你们昨天就应该来登记入住了
You were supposed to check in yesterday
结果却爽约了
But you didn't
所以房间送别人了
So we gave your rooms away
来看看还能怎么办
Let me see what we can do
有了
Here we go
不过比你们之前预约的房间烂一些
Though it's not as nice as
your previous accommodations
就住一晚而已
It's just for one night
还能烂到哪去
How bad can it be?
还不算太烂
Say, this isn't so bad
可以给你洗澡了
The shower's all yours
我累死了
I'm tired
要睡觉了
I'm just going to sleep
爱咋咋地
As you wish
别靠过来
Keep to your side
你吃得床上到处是碎屑
You're getting crumbs in the bed
我去卫生间睡了
I'm going to sleep in the bathroom
随你便
Suit yourself
什么
What?
他果然把卫生间全搞乱了
Of course he destroyed the bathroom
不过  这还挺高档
But hey, this is fancy
毛地毯
Shag carpeting
那不是地毯
That's not carpet
这是你的体毛吗
Is this your body hair?
你什么毛病
What is wrong with you?
太可怕了
The horror
你还挺高兴的
Well, you look chipper
昨晚睡得舒服吗
Did you sleep well?
没有
Nope
但你马上就要参加垃圾漫展去了
But soon you'll be at your lame comic convention
可以离我远远的了
far away from me
这倒能让我开心几下
That is something to smile about
确实
Agreed
但你的竖笛大会更是垃圾多了
But your Clarinet Con is, by far, the lamer of the two
漫画书
Comic books
起码我们竖笛家
Well, at least we clarinetists
可不会披着白痴披风
don't wear stupid capes
说反了吧
You were saying?
欢迎各路阿宅书呆
那是
Is that
老头简金斯
Old Man Jenkins?
该死
Gadzooks
不要不要
No, no
降落只要能成功逃生  就还算可以
Any landing you can walk away from is a good landing
不要
No
无辜的漫画书  全没了
All those innocent comic books, lost
打脸了吧
In your face
我还能去参加竖笛大会
I still get to go to my clarinet convention
你什么都看不着
and you get nothing
你输了
You lose
果然
Of course
最烂
Worst
旅行
Trip
非这莫属
Ever
大家都去哪了
Where did everybody go?
火车站
The train station
开往  裤头村
无票不得乘车
No tickets, no ride
你们还欠我半架飞机
You boys owe me half a plane
果不其然
Typical
慢点
Slow down
你快伤到我胳膊了
You're hurting my arms
他们就在那  小朋友
There they are, Junior
追过去
After 'em
我恨你  兄弟
I loathe you, chum
章鱼狂想盒
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
清理阁楼的事情都拖了好久了
I have put off cleaning my attic for way too long
小蜗小时候的壳
Gary's baby shell
小孩子长得真快
They grow up so fast
我的想象力盒子
My imagination box
不知道还能不能用
I wonder if it still works
天啊  现在来启动
Oh, boy, it's time for
想象力
imagination
真奇怪
That's weird
邻居
Hey, neighbor
能借杯沙子吗
Can I borrow a cup of sand?
我全用光了
I'm all out
那不是那啥
Isn't that the?
就是
It is
不过启动不了
But it won't start
我看看我能不能让它启动
Let me see if I can get it going
我们需要专业人士
We need a professional
想象力
盒子修复站
想象力盒子修复站
Imagination Box Repair
我们到了
This is the place
欢迎光临
Welcome
双重波纹3600
A double corrugated 3600
我已经有25年没见过这款了
I haven't seen one of these in 25 years
请问有什么问题
What seems to be the problem?
灵感马达不转了
Well, the inspiration motor won't turn over
破玩意坏了
Dern thing's on the fritz
对
Yeah
还用不了
And it doesn't work
让我看看盖子底下
Let me take a look under the flap
问题就在这边
Well, there's your problem
你们的盒子有个异想天开垫片烧了
Your box has blown a whimsy gasket
那种东西已经停产了
They don't make those anymore
不过你们买坐垫堡垒有优惠哦
But I could give you a great deal on a cushion fort
出售
不用  没事
No, that's okay
我只爱纸盒子
I'm a cardboard man
这破盒子现在纯垃圾了
This dumb ol' box is just junk now
别踩我沙子
Get off my sand
怎么回事
What's happening?
我在哪
Where am I?
就在我的想象力盒子里
Inside my imagination box
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
你肯定是撞到哪里  阴差阳错修好了
You must have jostled something and fixed it
派大星
Patrick
章鱼哥一定是迷路了
Squidward must be lost
迷失在自己的
Lost in his own
想象力
Imagination
我在里面啥都看不到
I can't see a thing in here
我需要手电筒
I need a flashlight
想象一个手电筒就好了
Just imagine a flashlight
对就有鬼了
Oh, yeah, right
想象手电筒  手电筒就会出现
I'll just imagine it and it'll appear
怎么
What the--
成功了
It worked
走哪里才可以出去呢
Now, where's the way out of here?
我要走了
I'm leaving
这个鬼地方怎么出去
How do I get out of this crazy place?
很简单  章鱼哥
That's easy, Squidward
让你想要去的地方浮现在眼前
Just visualize where you'd rather be
我更想离你们远远的
I'd rather be far away from you
远到奢华海滩度假村去
Like at a fancy beach resort
在躺椅上放松
And relaxing on a lounge chair
小啜热带饮料
Sipping a tropical drink
这想象力也还不错嘛
Maybe this imagination thing isn't so bad after all
你现在在干什么
What are you doing now?
你们非得问的话
Well, if you must know
我现在在伞底下放松
I'm relaxing under an umbrella
周围都是美丽的热带植物
surrounded by beautiful tropical plants
听起来你好像在丛林里
Sounds like you're in a jungle
不对
No
才不是
It's not a--
丛林
jungle?
丛林里不都是危险的动物吗
Aren't jungles full of dangerous animals?
对啊
Yep
比如说可怕的海蛇
Like scary sea snakes
你快救救我
You gotta help me
小心海黑豹
And look out for sea panthers
里面什么情况了  章鱼哥
How's it going in there, Squidward?
你们让情况变得更糟了
You're making everything worse
能不能别说话了
Would you two clam up?
蛤   蜊
我忘了提到吃衣服的蛤蜊了
I forgot to mention the clothes-eating clams
巨型蛤蜊
Giant clam
放开
Let go
那是我衣服
That's my shirt
太神奇了
Fantastic
现在我在丛林里迷了路
Now I'm lost in the jungle
身上一丝不挂
with no clothes on
那可不成问题
That's no problem
别忘了  你啥都能想象出来
Remember, you can imagine anything
想象是吗
Imagine, huh?
好
All right
不错
Not bad
丛林观兽探险还算有意思
A jungle safari could be fun
不管想象什么  都不要想
And whatever you do, don't imagine
一大群狂奔的海大象
a stampede of sea elephants
真谢谢你们了
Thanks a lot
不用谢
No problem
快告诉我
Now tell me
怎么逃离一大群狂奔的海大象
how to escape from a stampede of sea elephants
有热气球就行了
If only you had a hot air balloon
我一直都很想坐热气球
I've always wanted to ride in a balloon
我也想
Me too
有龙卷风就不想了
Unless there's a tornado
龙卷风
Tornado?
知道什么东西比龙卷风更棒吗
You know what's better than a tornado?
泡泡龙卷风
A bubble tornado
没事吧  章鱼哥
You okay, Squidward?
有事
No
他没事
He's okay
话说丛林里有恐龙吗
Say, are there dinosaurs in the jungle?
不要
Oh, no
我恨想象力
I hate imagination
我真高兴能看到章鱼哥
I'm so happy Squidward's having
探险玩得可嗨了
such an exciting adventure
怎么逃离这座丛林
How do I get out of this jungle?
试试想象你最爱的地方
Try imagining your favorite place
最爱的地方
Favorite place?
想到了
I've got it
爵士俱乐部
A jazz club
终于啊
Finally
有文化的地方
A place with culture
连咖啡都有爵士味
Even the coffee smells like jazz
好耶
Oh, yeah
沉浸在节奏里
Digging that groove
我们喜欢
We dig it
这咖啡味道像石头
This coffee tastes like rocks
摇 滚
一二三四
One, two, three, four
朋克摇滚
Punk rock?
全都发疯了
Everything's gone crazy
听起来你的想象力有点过于活跃了
Sounds like your imagination is overheating
脑袋放空一下
Try to clear your mind
脑袋放空
Clear my mind?
Clear my mind
你现在在哪  章鱼哥
Where are you now, Squidward?
我在一片空白里
I'm in an empty white void
不过起码很宁静
But at least it's peaceful
听起来好像是涂鸦次元
That sounds like the Doodle dimension
小心铅笔人
Watch out for DoodleBob
他长什么样
What's he look like?
他长得有点像这样
He looks kind of like this
能不能有谁
Would somebody please--
告诉我要怎么
Tell me how--
逃出这个
To get out of this--
白痴盒子
Stupid box
你这是想出去吗
You want out?
那怎么不早说
Well, why didn't you say so?
画个出口大门就行
Just draw an exit door
我没有笔啊
I don't have a pen
你可是章鱼
You're an octopus
全身都是墨水
You're full of ink
我回家了
I'm home
海绵宝宝跟派大星跑哪去了
Where did SpongeBob and Patrick run off to?
好吧
Oh, well
我要前往想象力消亡的地方去
I'm going to the place where imagination goes to die
蟹堡王
我枯燥没意义的最低工资工作
My dreary, pointless minimum wage job
又是那个无聊的蟹堡王
The good old boring Krusty Krab
真高兴能回来
I'm actually happy to be back
能为你点餐吗  先生
May I take your order, sir?
该提醒下他吗
Should we tell him?
不用  一听就知道他很开心
Nah, he sounds so happy
一份蟹黄堡套餐马上来
One Krabby combo coming up